실제 고객이 우리에게 “올해는 이혼을 막아준 것 같아”라고 말한 적이 있습니다.
We've had real customers say to us, "This year, I think you've saved me from getting a divorce."
[음악] Fixer는 고객, 동료, 그리고
[music] Fixer is an AI assistant for people managing clients, colleagues, and
일상 대화를 관리하며 중요한 것을 놓치지 않도록 돕는 AI 어시스턴트입니다. 이혼 상담가, 그는 실제 인물이며 정말 훌륭합니다.
conversations every day to make sure they don't miss anything important. The divorce guy, he's real and just awesome.
그의 이름은 마이크입니다. 그는 상업용 부동산 매니저로, 수백 개의 부동산과 수백 명의 사람들을 관리합니다. 그래서 하루 종일
He's called Mike. He's a commercial real estate manager, managing hundreds of different properties, hundreds of different people. and so all day on the
도로에서 문자 메시지를 보낼 수 없고, 저녁에 집에 돌아와 이메일을 따라잡아야 합니다. 하루에 1~2시간 정도
road can't text while driving and so comes home in the evening and has to like catch up on emails and that 1 to
가족과 제대로 시간을 보낼 수 없습니다. 우리는 마이크가 노트북을 열었을 때
two hours a day he's unable to like have proper family time. We want Mike to get to a place that when he opens his laptop
우선순위가 이미 정해져 있는 상태가 되길 원합니다. 모든 메일이 읽혔고, 정리되었으며,
the prioritizing has already been done for him. It's all been read. It's all been sorted and all the stuff that
실제로 필요한 내용이 바로 상단에 표시됩니다. Fixer는 팀 전체에 걸쳐 멀티플라이어 역할을 합니다.
actually needs him is right there at the top. fix and multipliers across the team
즉, 모든 사람이 중요한 일에 협업할 수 있어 놓치는 일이 없도록 합니다. [음악]
now, meaning everyone can collaborate on anything important to avoid anything slipping through the cracks. [music]
우리는 이 사무실에서 6개월째 근무하고 있습니다. 이제 모두 같은 층에 있는 것 같아요. [음악] 우리는 모두 함께 점심을 먹습니다.
We've been in this office 6 months. I think we're all in the same floor [music] now. Like we all have lunch
같이 먹으며 좋은 분위기를 느낍니다. >> 우리는 이미 ChatGPT가
together and it's just like a nice vibe. >> We already know that chat GBT is like
Fixer 외에 고객들이 가장 많이 사용하는 두 번째 AI 도구라는 것을 알고 있습니다.
the second biggest AI tool that our customers use besides Fixer.
>> 그들의 모델은 명백히 최첨단입니다. 새로운 모델이 출시될 때마다 훌륭한 것을 만들기가 정말 쉽습니다.
>> I mean, their models are obviously just state-of-the-art. So when they release a new model, it's really easy to create something really good.
>> 이곳은 실제 작업이 이루어지는 엔지니어링 부서입니다. 조이 엘로노라 데이비드입니다. 그들은
>> This [music] is engineering where all the real work happens. This is Joey Elonora David. They work closely with
OpenAI와 긴밀히 협력합니다. >> 회사 첫날, 저는 CTO 매트와 만나 '좋아,'라고 말했습니다.
OpenAI. >> Literally my first day at the company, I met with Mat CTO and he was like, "Okay,
당신의 일은 우리가 사람들에게 제공하는 초안을 더 나은 것으로 만드는 방법을 찾는 것이라고 했습니다. 다양한 부분이
your job is going to be to figure out a way to make the drafts that we generate for people better." Various parts of
이 흐름은 OpenAI를 사용해 통합됩니다. 그래서 우리는 모든 것에 OpenAI 모델을 사용합니다.
that flow are integrated using OpenAI. So we use open AI models for everything
이메일을 소화해 실제 내용이 무엇인지 파악하고,
from digesting the email so we can break down and understand what the email is actually about to pulling in and
우리가 포함하고 싶은 컨텍스트를 재정렬합니다. OpenAI 팀과 함께 일하며 놀라운 경험을 했습니다.
reranking the context that we want to include. We've had an amazing experience working with the team at OpenAI getting
모델을 개선하고 비용을 절감하며 효율성을 높이는 방법에 대한 의견을 듣고, 실제로 일부 기술적인
their thoughts on how we can improve our models, how we can improve cost, how we can make things more efficient and actually getting some of that technical
입력을 얻었습니다. [음악] >> 그래서 GPT-3가 출시된 순간이었습니다. 그때 저는
input as well. [music] >> So it was the release of GPT3. It was the moment where I just like got
예상했던 정확한 답을 받았습니다. 그래서 형이 전화를 걸어 '실제로 작동 중이야'라고 했습니다. 우리는 경영진용 [음악] 어시스턴트를 만들고 있습니다.
exactly the answer back that I expected. So my brother called me and he was like, "It's actually working." We've been building an executive [music] assistant
에이전시를 함께 구축했지만, Fixer를 가능하게 한 것은 OpenAI였습니다. 50만 시간의
agency together, but it was OpenAI that actually made Fixer possible. It allowed us to learn from the 500,000 hours
[음악] EA 워크플로우를 단 몇 달 만에 학습할 수 있게 해 주었습니다. 그 결과 첫 해에 우리는 0에서 3천만
[music] of EA workflows in just a matter of months. And the result of that was in our first year, we went from zero to 30
달러 ARR로 성장했습니다. [음악] Fixer가 비즈니스로 성공하고
million in ARR. [music] One of the real keys for Vixer succeeding as a business and delivering
다른 누구보다 나은 제품을 제공하는 핵심은 고객을 깊이 이해하는 힘든 작업을 수행하는 것이었습니다. 그리고 그때 OpenAI가
a better product than anyone else has literally just been about doing the hard work of learning our customer really well. And what Open AI was then really
우리에게 결정적이었던 것은 그 학습을 모델에 성공적으로 반영할 수 있었던 점이었습니다.
pivotal for us in doing was being able to take that learning and successfully
모델이 작동하는 방식에 통합하는 것이었습니다. YC 정신이 완전히
incorporate it into how the models work. I can see the YC mentality is absolutely
OpenAI 팀에 코딩되어 있는 것을 볼 수 있습니다. 언제든지 슬랙에 질문을 던지면
coded into the OpenAI team. At any moment, I can drop a question in Slack [music] and I've got an answer coming
빠르게 답이 돌아옵니다. 저는 매우 기업가적이고 역동적인 팀을 느낍니다. 솔직히 말하면
out pretty quickly. I've got what feels like a very kind of entrepreneurial [music] and dynamic team. Honestly, it
feels like a five-star hotel.